Damian Mandola Jr.

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/damianjr (713) 824-6195 dmandola11@gmail.com

After spending over ten years in restaurant and bakery management I have focused on switching fields to start a career in web development. I have always been intrigued and fascinated with technology and especially enjoy the creativity involved in front end development. With my background in customer service and management, I look forward to creating professional, responsive and user-friendly websites as part of my new career.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS

Austin, TX

Coding Boot Camp- Full Stack Web Development, Jul 2016 - Feb 2017

BOSTON UNIVERSITY

Boston, MA

BA, International Relations, September 2002 - May 2006

- Degree in International Relations with a focus on International Systems and World Order
- Student Leader for Project Hope, Community Service Center
- BU Red Cross Volunteer

JOHN CABOT UNIVERSITY

Rome, Italy

Study Abroad Program, September 2004 - May 2005

SKILLS

- Programming languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Node.js, Express, SQL, MongoDB, React.js
- Limited working proficiency in Spanish and moderate proficiency in Italian (dual Italian citizenship)
- Comprehensive experience with computer software including Aloha POS, Hotschedules and Microsoft Office

WORK EXPERIENCE

Instacart Austin

Full Service Shopper

Aug 2016 – Present

• Instacart is a technology company that offers a platform connecting grocery shoppers with customers. Combining a personal touch with cutting-edge technology, Instacart offers customers a simple solution to save time and buy directly from the retailers they trust. We give customers back their time so they can do more of what they love.

Mandola's Italian Market Austin, TX

Manager

Jan 2013 - Jul 2016

- Achieve company objectives in sales, service, quality, appearance of facility and sanitation and cleanliness through training of employees and creating a positive, productive working environment.
- Prepare all required paperwork, including forms, reports and schedules in an organized and timely manner.
- Ensure that all guests feel welcome and are given attentive, friendly and courteous service at all times.
- Establish standards for personnel performance and customer service.

Bakery Director Mar 2012 – Jan 2013

- Directly responsible for implementing and following company bakery standards and overseeing the bakery operations of all stores as well as inter-store deliveries.
- Meet with customers to discuss menus for special occasions, such as weddings, parties, or banquets.
- Analyze recipes to assign prices to menu items, based on food, labor, and overhead costs.

Mandola's Italian Market Bee Cave, TX

General Manager

Mar 2009 – *Feb* 2012

- Oversee and coordinate the planning, organizing, training, and leadership necessary to achieve stated objectives in sales, costs, profitability, employee retention, guest service and satisfaction, food quality, cleanliness, and sanitation.
- Manage staff, preparing work schedules through Hotschedules and assigning specific duties.
- Achieve company objectives in sales, service, quality, appearance of facility, sanitation, and cleanliness through training of employees and by creating a positive and productive working environment.

Mandola's Italian Market

Austin, TX

- Floor Manager

 Understand completely all policies, procedures, standards, specifications, guidelines and training programs.
- Ensure that all guests feel welcome and are given attentive, friendly and courteous service at all times.
- Control cash and other receipts by adhering to cash handling and reconciliation procedures in accordance with restaurant policies and procedures.